Products

Do it yourself

[CloudTax Free

Perfect for simple tax scenarios](https://cloudtax.ca/free)[CloudTax Plus

Recommended

Unlimited tax support](https://cloudtax.ca/plus)

File with an expert

[Personal Tax

Students, seniors & newcomers](https://cloudtax.ca/pro)[Self-Employment Tax

Business owners & freelancers](https://cloudtax.ca/self-employment-tax)[Emigrant & Non-resident Tax](https://cloudtax.ca/emigrant-nonresident-tax)[Corporate Tax

T2 tax returns](https://cloudtax.ca/corporate-tax)

Cloud Receipts

Store tax related documents easily

Start or continue your tax return

[2023

](https://app.cloudtax.ca/2023/auth/login)[2022

](https://www.app.cloudtax.ca/2022/auth/login)[2021

](https://www.app.cloudtax.ca/2021/auth/login)[2020

](https://www.app.cloudtax.ca/2020/auth/login)[2019

](https://www.app.cloudtax.ca/2019/auth/login)[2018

](https://www.app.cloudtax.ca/2018/)

Privacy Policy
--------------

At CloudTax, we are committed to protecting the confidentiality and privacy of personal information in our control and possession. This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains the procedures we put in place to achieve these commitments and describes the manner in which CloudTax collects, uses, discloses and otherwise treats personal information through our website available at [cloudtax.ca](https://simpletax.ca/), including all subpages and successor pages (collectively referred to as the “Website”) as well as through other communications with our users and potential users.

This Privacy Policy may be updated regularly to mirror changes to our personal information practices. We strongly encourage you to refer to this Privacy Policy frequently for the latest information about our personal information practices.

References to “CloudTax”, “us”, “we” or similar terms means CloudTax Inc.

Forms of personal information we collect
----------------------------------------

It is essential that CloudTax collects personal information from our users, either directly or through persons or entities acting on our behalf, in order to provide services to you. This information includes:

* personal information that you enter on an income tax form, including your name, address, social insurance number, and other identifying and contact information, in addition to your tax and financial information, and e-mail address;
* personal information that you enter or otherwise provide when you register or open an account, sign in, use a service, contact us for support, or give us feedback;
* information for billing and payment purposes, including credit or debit card information, such as card number and card expiration date; and
* analytic and usage data to improve CloudTax Service and ensure everything is working properly.

CloudTax restricts the collection of your personal information to the extent necessary to achieve the intentions identified at the time of collection.

How your personal information is used
-------------------------------------

The personal information we gather when you open an account is used for the following purposes:

* to enable you to successfully complete and file your tax return;
* to enable us prepare and file your returns where authorized to do so;
* to authenticate your identity and other information you have provided to us;
* to manage our operations;
* to improve our service offerings; and
* to fulfil legal and regulatory requirements.

Other ways we collect and use personal information
--------------------------------------------------

**Marketing Communications:** From time to time, we may obtain your consent to send you email, SMS text messages and other communications about CloudTax products, services, or events that may be of interest to you. You can opt-out of receiving marketing and promotional email from us by following the unsubscribe instructions contained in each of our email communications. Please note that you will continue to receive email regarding your account and transactions with us. Alternatively, you can unsubscribe from any of our marketing communications by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://cloudtax.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Customer Service/Relationship Manager:** If you contact us with a comment, question or complaint, you may be asked for information that identifies you (such as your name, address and a phone number) along with supplementary information we need to help us rapidly answer your question or reply to your comment, question, or complaint. We may keep this information to assist you in the future and to improve our customer service and, product and service offerings.

When we access users’ personal information
------------------------------------------

Notwithstanding any clause contained in this Privacy Policy, our users can choose which information we can access when they are not logged on to the Website, through their account settings. Certain personal information such as Social Insurance number, date of birth and mailing address shall be encrypted and only accessed by the password provided to you.

Restriction of disclosure of personal information
-------------------------------------------------

We will not disclose, trade, rent, sell or otherwise transfer your personal information, without your consent, except as otherwise set out in this Privacy Policy or as permitted or required by law.

* **Service Providers:** We may share your personal information with our service providers who provide various services on our behalf such as identity verification, technology, hosting, data analysis, research, legal and accounting.
* **Business Transactions:** We may transfer any information we have about you as an asset in connection with a prospective or completed merger or sale (including transfers made as part of insolvency or bankruptcy proceedings) involving all or part of CloudTax or as part of a corporate reorganization or stock sale or other change in corporate control, including for the purpose of determining whether to proceed or continue with such transaction or business relationship.

We take privacy seriously
-------------------------

We are responsible for ensuring that we adhere to this Privacy Policy. We invite any user or prospective user to contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://cloudtax.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) with any questions regarding this Privacy Policy. A user wishing to review his or her personal information in our possession should send a written request to this effect to us at CloudTax Inc., Suite 2201, 250 Yonge Street Toronto, Ontario M5B 2L7, Canada or call at 1-888-953-2112.

Access to your information
--------------------------

Individuals have the right to access, update, and correct inaccuracies in his/her personal information in CloudTax’s possession and control, subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law. You may update certain profile information through your account settings. Otherwise, an individual wishing to request access, updating and corrections of inaccuracies in other of his or her personal information in our possession or control may send a written request to this effect to CloudTax at the contact information below. We may request certain personal information for the purposes of authenticating the identity of the person seeking access to their personal information records.

CloudTax Inc.  
250 Yonge Street, Suite 2201  
Toronto, ON M5B 2L7

or

[\[email protected\]](https://cloudtax.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Collection and use of information about your visit to our website
-----------------------------------------------------------------

Generally, you can visit our Website without indicating who you are or submitting any personal information. However, we collect and/or maintain the IP (Internet protocol) addresses of all visitors to the Website and other related information such as page requests, browser type, operating system and average time spent on the Website. We use this information to help us understand Website activity and to monitor and improve the Website.

**Cookies & Similar Technologies:** The Website uses a technology called “cookies”. A cookie is a tiny element of data that the Website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your hard drive so that you can be recognized when you return. We use cookies on the pages on the Website where you are prompted to log in or that are customizable. If you have registered with the Website, these cookies may let us know who you are and identify your browser as one that has visited the Website before and may be necessary to access your account information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver products and personalized services. We also use cookies to provide us and our service providers with information about your use of the Website that we may use to personalize the Website or other content in accordance with your interests and preferences (e.g. language preference) and improve your user experience. You may set your Web browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to not accept certain cookies. However, if you decide not to accept cookies from the Website, you may not be able to take advantage of all the features of the Website.

**Tracer Tags & Web Beacons:** The Website may also use a technology called “tracer tags” or “Web Beacons”. This technology allows us to understand which pages you visit on the Website. These tracer tags are used to help us optimize and tailor the Website for you and other future visitors to the Website.

**Website Trackers & Analytics:** Mechanism like Google Analytics (this gives insight on how visitors find and use our website), Crazy Eggs (provides heatmaps on places visited on our website) and Pixel (used to optimize ads on Facebook and Instagram) may be used to help us gather and analyze information about the areas visited on the Website in order to better understand, evaluate and improve the user experience and the convenience of the Website.

**Social Media:** An opportunity may be offered to you to engage with our content on or through third-party social networking websites, plug-ins and applications. When you engage with our content on or through third-party social networking websites, plug-ins and applications, you may allow us to have access to certain information associated with your social media account (e.g., name, username, email address, profile picture, gender) to deliver the content or as part of the operation of the website, plug-in or application. When you provide information from your social media account, we may use this information to personalize your experience on the Website and on the third-party social networking websites, plug-ins and applications, and to provide you with other products or services you may request.

Online advertising
------------------

We may use third parties such as data companies and ad exchanges to serve our advertisements on our Website or other websites. These companies may use cookies, tracer tags, pixels or web beacons to report certain information about your visits to our Websites and other websites (such as web pages you visit and your response to ads) in order to measure the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns and to deliver ads that are more relevant and tailored to you, both on and off our Website.

To learn more about this behavioural advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit the Digital Advertising Alliance website at [www.aboutads.info/choices/](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/) or the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada website at [www.youradchoices.ca/choices](https://www.youradchoices.ca/choices).

We may provide links to third party websites
--------------------------------------------

Our Website may contain links to other websites that we do not own or operate. Also, links to our Website may be featured on third party websites on which we advertise. Save for as provided herein, we will not provide any of your personal information to these third parties without your consent. We provide links to third party websites as a convenience to the user. These links are not intended as an endorsement of or referral to the linked websites. The linked websites have separate and independent privacy policies, notices and terms of use, which we recommend you read carefully. We do not have any control over such websites, and therefore we have no responsibility or liability for the way the organizations that operate such linked websites may collect, use or disclose, secure and otherwise treat your personal information.

‍

Believe In Better

Follow us

Products

Company

© 2024 CloudTax Inc.
